# Kareem Khalil

## Full Stack Web Developer

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 8 years of related experience.

# **Work History**

2021-08

- present

## **Technical Lead Front-End Developer**

Vodafone \_VOIS, Egypt

Lead Technical development team, develop and manage (design/ build) sprints in the Web-Factory, Working Offshoring for Vodafone Germany

#### Responsibilities

- Lead and manage a squad of 5 Front-end developers with applying agile methodologies.
- Responsible of the design sprint activities and technical design meetings Page 1 of 4.
- Design technical solutions for the user stories and implement POCs when needed - Responsible of conducting technical assessment for new projects.
- Provide support for the scrum team in build sprint.
- Supervise and apply agreed quality gates (Code review, Unit test Coverage, ...) - Develop complex technical tasks and user stories.
- Responsible of delivery, technical estimate, sizing, and tasks assignation.
- Support scrum release activities.
- Work alongside Product Owner and UX lead to define product requirements.
- Support new-hires and manage coaching plans for smooth onboarding Spoc. and representative of technical team.
- Effectively communicate technical information to on-shore and off-shore team members and to non-technical audiences.
- Maintain and support production incidents, and provide instant hotfixes.
- Support releases and deployments on different environments.

2020-03

- 2022-01

#### **Senior Front-End Developer**

Vodafone \_VOIS, Egypt

Designs, Develop and manage Dev. team in the Vodafone Germany Account (WebFactory).

#### Responsibilities:

- Implement complex front-end modules with responsive design Deliver accurate technical estimates for efforts and size user stories based on both the business needs and the technical complexity with agile methodologies.
- Support team members in their tasks and manage onboarding plans for the newcomers.
- Design technical solutions for simple user stories.
- Write professional technical design documentation.
- Communicate directly with the channel managers.

### **Personal Info**

Email

kareem.moh.khalil@gmail.com

Phone

+201007769096

Date of birth

1990-03-01

**Marital status** 

Married

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/kareem-khalil

Website

http://kareemkhalil.me/

#### **Skills**

JavaScript programming

Node.js

Angular

ASP.NET MVC

CSS proficiency

HTML expertise

.NET development

Agile Methodologies

## Languages

English - C1

## 2019-01 Senior Full-Stack Developer

- 2020-03

Link Development, Egypt - Cairo

creates web products needed in order to accomplish particular goals that clients have. This can range from custom-made software to graphic designs. With using dot net framwork.

#### 2018-01

## **Full-stack Developer**

- 2018-12

Link Development, Egypt

Creates web products needed in order to accomplish particular goals that clients have. This can range from custom-made software to graphic designs. With using dot net framwork.

### 2017-03

### **Junior Software Engineer**

- 2018-02

AFA Technologies, Egypt

- Manipulated and implemented object-oriented programming models.
- Tuned and improved software source code based upon new user requirements and technical guidelines.
- Collaborated with fellow engineers to evaluate software and hardware interfaces.

## 2016-08

#### **Freelance Web Developer**

- 2020-01

Freelance, Egypt

- Implemented Google-based SEO and ad campaigns to meet budget specifications.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Provided security maintenance and patching on website interface to maintain viability after launch.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.

#### 2012-08

- 2018-01

## **Bank Employee**

QNB Group, Egypt

Operation Officer, At QNB (2016 to Present): Provides account services to customers by receiving deposits and loan payments; cashing checks; issuing savings withdrawals; recording night and mail deposits; selling cashier's checks, traveler's checks, and series e bonds; answering questions in person;

referring to other bank services.

#### **Education**

#### Commerce, Bachelor's

Ain Shams University, Cairo

# Microsoft Web Development, diploma

Inform institute (IBM partner), Cairo